# **TOMAS LOZANO**

Phone: 343 777 6214 ■ Email: tomaslozanol@gmail.com

Front-end web developer, app and software developer with 3+ years of experience and 6 years of experience in business administration. Held different jobs allowing pursue an interest in both degrees.

Thank to these experiences I have developed skills like work well in groups, fast learner, and develop strong interpersonal and leadership skills. Become well versed in working with SQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React and currently working on a project for a Mobile App as well as a website using Python for a web scrapper.

## **Skills**

Languages: Java, Python Frameworks/Libraries/CMS: Bootstrap, jQuery, JSON,

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, WordPress, React

XML, Sass Databases: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB Back-end: PHP Others: Android Studio, GitHub, Jira

# Experience

## IT Customer Service (Contract)

FOKO RETAIL - Ottawa, ON, Jul 2020 - Sep 2020

- Updated user manual for the new operative system, implementing options for desktop and cellphone
- Using MongoDB and JavaScript, created a few scrips to help with data search in their database, improving daily routines
- Worked with Jira to connect any customer's problem that might come out after launch of the new operative system

### Front-End Web Developer (Co-Op)

PATIO CONCEPTS INC. - Ottawa, ON, Jan 2018 - May 2018

- Redesigned the company's website, implemented new designs, and improved the user experience using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript
- Improved web site's speed by 15%, by implementing a more efficient code using HTML5 and Bootstrap

#### **Quotation Engineer**

TPI S.A. - Santiago, Chile, Oct 2015 - Aug 2016

 Identified inquiries from potential clients, reviewed project scope, provided engineering quotes and finalized deals for clients in the mining and stainless-steel metal industry

# Marketing, Web Analyst

SIG SIG S.A. – Santiago, Chile, Jan 2013 – Sep 2015

- Reduced merchandise cost by 25%, by reviewing conditions with current providers and searching for better options of potential ones, within the first two months
- Implemented internet marketing strategy Search Engine Optimization (SEO) to improve website visibility and raising potential clients visits by a 10%

#### Education

ALGONQUIN COLLEGE - Ottawa, Canada

Diploma in Computer Programming, Sep 2016 – Dec 2018

DEL DESARROLLO UNIVERSITY - Santiago, Chile

Bachelor's Business Administration Engineering, Mar 2005 – Jul 2010

Portfolio: github.com/tomasLozano